Is the pain relieving effect of
nandrallone mediated by other mechanisms
other than its role as a progesterine?
I.e. does it actually does it have any
kind of unique opioid or
anti-inflammatory functions outside of
just increasing fluid in the joint?
There's no question that does have a
significant joint pain rate. One of them
that I don't know if this is the reason
or not that it increases synovial fluid.
Even though it's not equal, I tend to
start by reducing the testosterone dose
by about 50 60 millig and then in and
then adding nandulone at 60 millig and
then it's about the same thing we always
do. Titrate the dose of none up if
necessary to ease the joint pain. I
think one of the main things that people
are so worried about estrogen I don't
think it they need to be. So then I was
going to go into another one of my
methodologies that has worked really
well for me over the decades with
dealing with estrogen is the use of
andone. So now what I can do is I can
pull your testosterone dose back to
whatever does not cause an estrogenic
side effect. Different studies that say
there that nandrulin converts to zero to
20 20% to estradile that testosterone
does. I have found that it actually
probably is closer to zero. So what I
can do is just is give people
testosterone at a dose that doesn't
cause estrogenic side effects. But us
sometimes for people who are sensitive
that's not enough testosterone. They
need more androgens in their blood. They
need more androgen receptor agonization.
So now we can just pop mandulin on top
of that and there's no estrogenic side
effects and then people do really well
on that. I mean do you notice the same
issue and and what do you think about
about that?
Yeah. So, I'll I'll kind of share all my
tricks of the trade and and absolutely
I'd be I'd be very happy if you steal
that and any others because I think one
thing that we both have in common is
we're both trying to educate as much as
possible in this in this space because
my goal is if we can get as many people
with properly optimized testosterone
protocols as possible all over the world
that and I can only see so many people a
day before my eyes start to bleed from
the computer screen. I'd like to ask you
a bunch of stuff about Nangelone that um
I've been wanting to ask someone for a
long time, but I haven't met anyone
who's really clued into it in terms of
not just being like, "Oh yeah, when you
give it to someone this happens in terms
of being like what's actually happening
and why, but in terms of the the the
stuff that you brought up there that the
the really important point that you
brought up is that a lot of the problems
that people have when they start TRT is
because your hormones went from here to
here really really quick. Um, and I like
to mitigate that by kind of coming in
with a a dose that I refer to like,
okay, we're going to start you off with
like a single shot cappuccino, then
we'll move it up to like a double shot
flat wide, and then we're going to move
it up to a triple espresso. We're not
just going to go straight for the triple
espresso. Yeah. Um, so dose titration
can be really important. But when I
started TRT almost a decade ago, and
this was, you know, I think Jay Campbell
had just put his first book out. There
was maybe the Excel Mail forum had
started, but there was nothing on
YouTube. And that's one of the reasons I
got into making content because I just
tried to make what I was looking for
many years ago. But at least the benefit
of that was that there wasn't a whole
bunch of stuff that you could just go
down like doom scrolling and just screw
yourself up with anxiety with. You just
kind of had to like trust the process.
And my doctor said to me when I started
my protocol and granted it it it was 250
milligrams every 10 days with uh half a
milligram of rumex twice a week and and
hcg which was not a good place to start
but what he did say in his defense is he
goes when you start your treatment if
you have any side effects at your first
followup we'll talk about it and he was
basically saying that this is going to
be an adjustment phase And at the moment
I see a lot of guys, they become
hyperfixated with every sensation in
their body and they immediately have a
panic anxiety response to it. And this
can often lead them to making, you know,
emotional responses or derailing the
protocol or um really creating some
issues. But I like to tell them, I'm
like, look, this is going to be puberty
2.0. Like this is going to be another
hormone process, but now you're an adult
with responsibilities. you've got, you
know, all the information in the world
in the palm of your hand. This can
really go haywire if you're not prepared
to go through some change. And sometimes
guys will freak out and they'll go, "Oh,
this is changing. This is changing. This
is changing." And I'm going, "Well,
maybe you should frame this as, well, at
least something's happening. I mean, if
nothing was changing, then it wouldn't
be working." So, you kind of got to pick
something, right? But it's, look, it's
exactly what you said. A lot of the
estrogen issues that people are having
when they're starting treatment that
they call estrogen issues is part of the
body getting with the program. There's a
whole bunch of downstream enzyatic stuff
that has to reregulate and change and
that process you're going to inhabit
that and that that's going to be tricky.
But the other thing that I found and one
of the and and I'm sure you're the same.
One of the the best things about working
with so many people for so long is that
you learn a bunch of stuff from just
basically you you can show me a study
saying the sky is green. I'm outside all
day every day. It's blue. Um and this
kind of stuff we learn from TRT is that
we're going I'm I'm in the trenches all
the time. But one thing that's been a
real blessing for me is as you know some
some co-founders have have helped uh set
up clinics that I'm very heavily
involved with. I end up seeing you know
10 to 20 times more people per week
because I'm doing asynchronous reviews
of the blood work. So I'm seeing huge
volumes now and then trends become a lot
more apparent because you're seeing a a
a client's blood work every five minutes
not every 20 or 30 minutes. Yeah. And
the thing that I find really interesting
and and the way that I've designed our
questionnaires for, you know, follow-ups
and feedback so that we can make some
succinct recommendations for their
conversation with the doctor is around
lifestyle factors. And if I had to
correlate two variables almost
perfectly, it would be alcohol
consumption and side effects at 12
weeks. Um, and then if I had to bring a
couple of other variables into that
equation, it's excess body fat and
terrible diet. And the issue that I
think people are having like, and if you
go on Reddit, the problem is that you
can see all these genetic overromatizers
who don't have profile pictures. I think
if they had profile pictures, very
quickly work out that this is a body fat
problem. Um, or an alcohol problem. I
mean, how many of those guys would have
a beer in their hand in their photos?
So, it's it can sometimes be a very
tricky thing to change these habits
because a lot of these habits are
maladaptive coping mechanisms from
people feeling terrible for a long time
and they're now having to, you know,
kind of recognize and sometimes learn
the hard way that this stuff's not
serving them anymore. But I think that
outside of protocols being terrible,
like assuming that we're dealing with
frequent injections and and you know,
decent doses of testosterone, I think
that half of the side effects come from
the body adjusting to the protocol. And
the other half come from the systemic
inflammation from poor diet and
lifestyle factors as well as poor liver
function, chronic pain, chronic
inflammation, all of these things
together. And then some these guys I
think are a real challenge because one
of the problems where you know things
kind of the pendulum swings too far in
each direction is people go oh well it's
it's not an estrogen issue and it's
going okay but it is an issue like
there's there's still a problem here we
need to fix this. So if we're not going
to use aromatase inhibitors aren't the
solution it's like there has to still be
a solution otherwise you just got a
problem. So, I think that's where it
becomes case by case and I think that it
can be a matter of manipulating the
protocol, making sure there's not things
like hypothyroidism going on. Um, I've
never used an angelone for something
like this. I'm very curious about that.
But also for me, it's with my health
coaching background, it's going, hey, we
need to change the habits. And sometimes
it can be, you know, prescribing things
like glutathione injections, uh, giving
people melatonin at night to help with
sleep and to help modulate, you know,
inflammation and estrogen receptor
availability. All of these things can be
really helpful. But ultimately, it comes
down to going if you are putting the
healthy amount of testosterone into a
healthy man at a frequency that at least
mimics natural production as closely as
possible. It shouldn't cause problems.
it should make you healthy and that's
just how the works. So, I'd like to kind
of hijack the conversation a little bit
like we spoke about before. I I've
always been curious about Nangalone and
I was curious about it originally
because I'm a big fan, not a cult
follower, but I'm a fan of Dr. Ray
Pete's work. Um, and I make that
distinction very importantly and he was
very big on progesterone. Um, so I was
always very interested in Nandrallone in
terms of it being this, you know,
anabolic compound that also had this
progesterone or progesterine-like
effect. And the thing that I've never
been able to understand and I've looked
at the research and the research was it
was mentioning stuff but it wasn't very
clear. So what I'd be curious about is
well actually two parts. One is the pain
relieving effect of
Nandrallone mediated by other mechanisms
other than its role as a progesterine
i.e. does it actually does it have any
kind of unique opioid or
anti-inflammatory functions outside of
just increasing fluid in the joint? And
then secondly, what kind of dose is
typically well tolerated both from not
causing things like bloating or high
blood pressure or or mood side effects
and how does that kind of in in practice
what does that typically look like with
TRT? Yeah, great great questions and and
and I can luckily I have a lot of
experience and I've uh been able to uh
resolve that experience with data and
studies as well and and one of the
problems is there's not a lot of studies
done on mandalone and that's one that's
one of the problems right first of all
what I wanted to say is I loved what you
said about yeah the studies you can I
can you can show me a study that says
the sky is green I'm outside every day
the sky is blue I say that a lot and and
I frame it by saying that studies are
interest and they should invoke further
look into things, but what's more
important is the empirical data. What do
we actually see in the field and that
trumps anything that a stud is going to
tell you and and then when you said uh
you can just start to see trends because
you do this so much and that's kind of
what what happened to me throughout the
decades. I've successfully got over
20,000 people through the use of
hormones. So I can sit on my mountain
top look down on all the empirical data
I've aggregated and I can start to see
these trends that other people can't. I
can start to see how percentages of
populations move with different things
and you know because of my background
too I've done a lot of the derivatives
uh
nandrallones balden oxandrelone even
even methanolone and that's another
thing too methanolone the fact that well
in the United States anyways that it's
not a it's not FDA approved is a
testament to how little the medical
community understands these because
methanol is incredibly beneficial and
would really solve a lot of especially
like when people have the estrogenic
issues or it would really solve that and
methanol is a when we want to talk about
a safe anabolic androgenic steroid that
has a lower side effect profile than
anything else. I mean the fact that we
don't use that is just silly but I
really loved what you said there and I
wanted I wanted to highlight that. Um
moving into nangeloinone. So yeah I've
used nulin quite a bit. I've had
thousands and thousands of people and
I've had a lot of success with it. And
so one of the the things that develops
is the myth of decadade, right? And and
that's one of the first things people
always say to me. And decad just comes
from a low estrogen issue. It does not
convert to estrogen. So back in the
early 2000s, late 90s, early 2000s,
anabolic steroids were actually hard to
come by and people would take whatever
they could get their hands on. So they
would get their hands on a bottle of
Nandril and just take it by itself
without understanding the need for the
balance of testosterone and estrogen. So
it would shut down their indogenous
testosterone supply, therefore shut off
the conversion to estrogen and they'd
have all this nandelone with no estrogen
and then one of the classic symptoms of
low estrogen is erectile dysfunction. So
that's where the myth of decadic was
born. On the contrary, when we use
nandolone properly with testosterone
because of its progesterrotogenic
nature, I usually actually get benefits
in libido, benefits in erection quality
because it does have a 20% affinity to
the progesterone receptor. Now when I
see blood tests and I see men with um
below.5 progesterone I always say okay
this is a problem and like you I wanted
to start with pregnentoolone. I want to
try to see if we can get some some the
steroidenesis and get some progesterone
in there with with the use of
pregnenolone first. It's import it's
important it's a work acts on GABA
receptors. It's a you know kind of for
anti-anxiety. It also has to do erectile
function libido and sensitivity as well.
But we can also use nandrin as a
progesterine to hit that function as
well. So going further into its joint
joint relief and and again there is no
study that clearly highlights this is
the reason that nandelone notoriously
reduces joint pain but it is absolutely
undeniable that it does. There is way
too much anecdotal data. I've seen it
thousands of thousands upon thousands of
times myself and I've read about it a
hundred thousand more times. Right? So
there's no question that nandrolone does
have a significant joint pain rate. Some
of the mechanisms that we start to that
we have looked into and I have a few
that I that I think are probably the
reason. One of them that I don't know if
this is the reason or not that it
increases synovial fluid. Um whether or
not that's a progesteric activity as
well and it's not proven that it
increases synenovial fluid that's a
theory but that would make sense. It's
just systemically anti-inflammatory.
Systemically more anti-inflammatory than
than even testosterone. testosterone is
Dr. Edward Liken. So he pioneered some
research on using anabolic steroids for
inflammatory diseases and he found that
nangeline was one of the most
anti-inflammatory and this is just
through research and and trial and
error. And he used a lot of anabolic
steroids to treat inflammatory diseases
such as Crohn's disease, ulcer of
colitis. These happen to be digestive
like autoimmune inflam inflammatory
diseases but also rheumato rheumatoid
arthritis. and he would find he even
found and wrote that Nandrulin was one
of the best at this. So just a
systemically anti-inflammatory nature.
Again, that's kind of what we're looking
what's the reason for that. What I had
been looking for for a long time was any
evidence that Nandrallone had some sort
of agonization on the gluccocorticoid
receptor because that would be it,
right? That would explain it. And I
found no evidence that Nandeline
directly had agonized the
gluccocorticoid receptor. And I was
hoping to because that would be an easy
answer. After studying this a lot and
and just over over years and years of
doing research, I finally found one
study that did show that one of
Nandrulin's metabolites, progesterine
metabolites, does agonize
gluccocorticoid receptor. That's
probably what I feel would do it the
most. If we agonize the gluccocorticoid
system, then we would reduce
inflammation to the point that we would
have joint pain relief. Here's another
thing I factor I found, and this could
be and it could be all these things
together, right? It could be a little
bit of all this together creates this
this system that really just helps pain.
What I also found is that nor's
nandrallone does have a small affinity
for the estrogen receptor alpha. This
would also explain why bodybuilders so
what would happen is bodybuilders would
be taking a pretty high dose of
testosterone and then all a sudden and
they'd be fine, right? Then they'd add a
pretty high dose of nandelone and they'd
get gynecomastia. Now the whole idea
that tenantulin doesn't convert to
estrogen and we kind of show that so so
you know some bodybuilders would say
well it must convert to estradile
because I got gynecomastia when I added
it but you know it's just we prove over
and over again that it does not so then
that's when the whole thing about
prolactin well something's got to be
doing that so maybe it's prolactin and
then that's when Llewellyn William
Luwellen had to disprove that nandelone
universally increased prolactin it does
not it's actually rare that it does so I
found that nandrallone in high doses,
right? It's a dose dependent manner will
agonize the estrogen receptor alpha and
that makes the most sense when we add a
high because it's really only high
doses. When we have testosterone and we
had a high dose of nandelone then some
people who are sensitive to gynecomastia
will will get gynecomastia and it's
probably because it's directly agonizing
the estrogen receptor. Now that also
could induce joint pain relief, estrogen
receptor agonization. So it it could be
kind of a kind of all these things
together that would do that. But I have
had a lot of success with Nandrulin as
far as increasing people's sense of
well-being, reducing anxiety, giving
people increased libido, increased
erection quality when used properly. It
just has to be used properly. Every once
in a while, and I would say it's even
less than one out of a hundred, you have
somebody who just does not react well to
the end. They have like mental anxiety
effects. And it's rare, but every once
in a while it does happen. Of course,
those are the people who speak the
loudest on on TRT forums or or forums.
So, everybody goes, "Oh, no. I read
about that." I was like, "No, it really
doesn't happen that often. If it does
happen, you can just discontinue the
Nashville and you'll go back to normal.
Everything will be fine." In fact, our
friend Danny Bosa there was one that
experienced that. He just couldn't take
none without without the medical mental
side effects. But, it's very rare that
that happens. think it's it's it's it's
interesting and it's a fascinating one
for me as someone who's done a lot of
research into progesterone in men which
is such a a poorly understood subject
and people often you know bring across a
whole bunch of the mechanisms of
progesterone in in women and then say oh
that means that men should take the same
dose of progesterone the women do and
it's like well that's like saying women
should take a man's dose of testosterone
that's not it it still has the the same
properties in in the brain and it is so
integral
for for balance. And the way that I
often explain progesterone in both men
and women is that progesterone is kind
of like the brain's version of Valiant.
You know, it's a positive alossteric
modulator of the GABA A receptor. And
when you have a deficiency in that, it's
kind of like you're having a Valium
withdrawal all the time. And it's it's
one of the hormones that declines with
age in men. And my general go-to for
that has always been to optimize with
pregnenolone because that way we know
that pregnenolone predominantly converts
into progesterone. It's like a 70%
conversion. Um and that way the body can
kind of pull from that what it needs as
it needs it. And one of the things that
I found to be a gamecher and I always go
back to to Dr. Keith Nichols because he
was right about a lot of things that I
used to kind of question was that the
sustained release use of pregnenolone,
so like a sustained release capsule,
allows the body to really create that
optimal level of progesterone
consistently without these kind of peaks
and troughs. But I've always had this
interest in in Nandrulone because I've
met people and only a small handful of
them because nandelone's a bit tricky in
Australia, but methanolone's not. And
that's one of the uh good things about
Australia is like I often joke that in
the US you guys only use Anavar
therapeutically because you can't get
methanolone but um methanolone's
wonderful when it's used properly. I
mean that's you you give someone 25
milligrams of methanol. I've never seen
that disregulate any blood markets ever.
I mean it's so well tolerated and so so
beneficial especially for these younger
guys who who really need a bit more of
that androgenic kind of oomph. But when
it comes to this this Nandrallone thing,
the the other thing that I'm I'm really
curious of is like because when I've
read the research on it, there's there's
that one study and I often joke that I'm
like, you know, when we were doing our
undergrad in in science and and one
thing that I'll kind of, you know, cover
back on is that you refer to basically
what I what I often say is that science
is a tool that helps us understand the
world. It's not a religion. Recently,
people have started to worship it like
it's a religion. And the whole point of
the the scientific method is to go, I've
got this idea. Let's attack it from
every angle and see if it still holds up
to be true. And that's basically the
scientific method. And the thing that
you you learn when you when you study
science, you know, when we do our first
year, you know, science 101 um unit,
they'd give you a study and they'd
remove like the discussion or they'd
remove the the abstract or they'd remove
the conclusion and you had to fill in
the the blanks. And one thing that you
learn when you do that exercise is you
go, these studies are often a load of
[__] They don't mean anything compared
to what the a like sometimes the author
just gets it backwards. Um or they're
wasting something that's just nonsense.
Like it's just nonsense conclusions. And
the thing that I've had trouble with for
nandelone is that you've got this one
study that goes, we added 50% of the TRT
dose in Nandelone to a TRT protocol and
then we measured people's self-reported
pain relief. I'm like, that's that's
barely a study. It's like we measured
one thing and we we did this kind of
thing and it was just like okay, but
what else happened? And they're like,
well, we didn't look at that. So that
but you know what they did look at is
interesting but then in all these other
studies I'm seeing 25 mg per mill
nandalone decinoate administered every 2
to 3 weeks in HIV patients. So I'm
sitting here being like well in these
studies where they've used next to
nothing at least they've measured some
kind of you know other blood markers and
then in the one that kind of represents
the dosing that I see a lot of people
doing online they didn't really measure
anything. So what kind of ballpark like
weekly like starting dose, average dose,
like what or is there a dose that you
start with and then you have to work it
up to confer therapeutic benefit or is
there a dose that if you go too high it
causes problems? Like what kind of like
what does this really kind of look like
in practice? Yeah, that's a another
great question. So So I think we attack
it like we attack anything else. start
off at a low dose and I found that about
60 milligrams is where people can start
to see the benefits of nandelone
depending on what we've done with the
testosterone but it is it is an androgen
it will increase the total androgen load
so we got to we want to watch that we're
not going too high so I have some people
who they go up to like 250 testosterone
per week right now they start saying man
these joint pains won't go away or
something something to that effect and
so I say okay well I think it makes
sense instead of just adding and on top
of that the androgen load's getting
high. Let's back off testosterone and
then add nandeline, right? So, we'll
just even though testosterone is more
anabolic than than nandelone, it's
nandelone is much less androgenic than
testosterone. So, even though it's not
equal, I tend to start by reducing the
testosterone dose by about 60 milligram
50 60 milligrams and then in and then
adding nandelone at 60 milligrams. And
then it's about the same thing we always
do. titrate the dose of none up if
necessary to continue to mitigate the
side effects or continue to to ease the
joint pain. So, and I find that you know
everybody's different, right? Some some
people their magic number is 100
milligrams
nandelone. The the classic thing that
people say is you got to do a 2:1 ratio
and that's just I mean that's a that's a
that's an okay start. Some people really
most people are just fine with a 1:1
ratio testosterone and again it would
have to do with total androgen load to
the estrogen ratio like what what works
for that person as an individual and
also the progesterrogenic activity like
there can be too much and also
understand this for people who are super
sensitive to estrogen we'll give more
nandelone than testosterone I've had
people who are so sensitive to
testosterone and the the estrogenic
conversion that they can only use 50
milligrams per week of testosterone. And
so then now that's just not enough
androgens. They need more androgens, but
they can't add testosterone. So then we
just I I'll put 100 milligrams of
nandrulin on top of that. So now we're
doing more nandulone than testosterone.
And for some people who are really
sensitive to that estrogen, that works
really really well. For most people, you
do want it a 2:1 or 1:1 ratio, but a 1:1
ratio doesn't necessarily confer
problems. Um, and sometimes it can that
the extra proestester progesteric
activity can actually cause can start to
cause erection quality problems or
sensitivity problems. So, it's about
finding that ratio. So, just like we do
anything else, start off low, slowly
titrate up until we find the dose that
yields the best results for you as an
individual. But, it's very beneficial. I
I recommend the use of nandrulonein for
any kind of joint pain or like I've had
people who just having a little anxiety
from from testosterone probably because
you know it's a it increases tyrroscen
kynise tyrroscenase increases the
catakolamines such as norepinephrine and
and epinephrine the progesteric effect
can like you said it acts on the gabber
receptors can kind of quiet the mind it
can kind of reduce anxiety so I can use
it for for that function as well but
yeah I I have a lot of success with
Angela like it it adds and benefits
people's protocol. I I think that the
amazing thing about hormone replacement
therapy is that like you know there's
not really many painkillers you can use
chronically that are good for you that
are still going to maintain efficacy
without you really pushing it up and
creating issues. I mean you've got NSA
which will destroy your gut. You've got
paracetamol that will destroy or opioids
which will destroy your life. So, I
mean, it's uh it's when when you've got
a tool a tool in the toolbox to be like,
hey, we've got something here that I
mean, and I think that's one of the
wonderful things about this field is you
don't need that many tools because the
tools are so effective for so many
things. Yeah, that's really interesting.
I I've seen these compounds get so many
people off of all other kinds of kinds
of medications, including opioids for
pain relief. I've seen nandelone and
testosterone combination get so many
people off of opioids. Um, we did I've
done a few videos of people who were
able to do just that. Um, we did
transformation stories of people who
were in really bad injuries and were on
opiates and now they just use
testosterone and to control their pain
and they don't need opiates anymore.
It's it's wonderful. That was that was
actually the the catalyst that made me
reach out to you before for for people
listening before we were recording. I
was saying that one of the downsides of
being so busy is you don't really watch
much of this stuff in your free time
because you just want to kind of watch
something else. Um, but one of the
videos that I saw of yours outside of
your the previous one that I'd watched
was yeah, you were sharing like a case
study of of a guy who and he was kind of
going through like a like a pain log.
And you know, as someone myself who's
experienced a lot of chronic pain in my
life from spinal injuries, like when
someone can sit there and be like, "No,
like this is like significantly better."
you know, from like a low out of 10 to
like, you know, eight or nine out of 10
pain relief from not having to use
opioid medication or like massive doses
of NSAs. I mean, that's that's that's
that's miracle work for people who are
suffering with that stuff. Couldn't
agree with you more and and I've that's
why you and I are both in this field
because we've seen miracles and just
like you said, I love how you just put
that. I'm probably going to steal that
too is we have these tools in our teal
box and we don't need too many tools
because it really it really you know a
lot of people hate when I say this but
it almost becomes a panacea for for all
of these disorders for metabolic
disorders fatigue disorders and a lot of
a lot of pain pain as well because we're
we're really fixing the root of the
problem. We're fixing the ideology from
metabolic disorders and from fatigue
disorders. Like we're getting to the
root of what's causing those. And it it
really is a great tool to no matter what
the what the ideology of those disorders
are, these hormones can come in and and
fix it. And the the thing that kind of
what you were talking about before with
how, you know, testosterone increases
part of the the tyroine conversion,
which for people listening is basically
how dopamine gets made from amino acids.
One of the things that I've learned from
from Dr. Keith as well as uh Neil Rusier
as well is this idea of if we optimize
the hell out of one hormone, then it can
often be really important that we
optimize the other pathways of the body
to be able to support this part of the
body being optimal. I mean, if you and I
use I've used this analogy to death, but
if you have a car that needs a service
and then you supercharge the engine,
then you're going to fix one problem but
create a few more because now there's
further imbalance between these systems.
And I think that sometimes one of the
challenges for people in chronic pain or
people with metabolic disorders is that
we've taken a really healthy level of
testosterone and put it in someone who's
really unhealthy. And the process of
getting them to be able to meet that
medicine halfway in terms of getting
healthier sometimes requires supporting
more systems. And I think that this is
where if a guy's got low testosterone
and low progesterone, then you know he
might not really notice that cuz he just
feels terrible anyway. But now if you
jack the testosterone up, all of a
sudden he's like, I I feel better, but
I'm over stimulated because now that low
progesterone is now problematic because
we fixed one thing, but we've now
created this gap between the two.
[Music]